# Alexander J. Davis

Riverview, FL, 33578 | 813-465-8252 | ajdavis2424@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/alexander-davis-3674716a https://ajdavis2424.github.io/Professional-Portfolio/ https://ajdavis2424.github.io/gtech\_react\_profile/

# Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in management, employee development, and customer service. Earned certificate in Full-Stack Web Development through Georgia Tech , and earned a MBA from Saint Leo University in 2020. While completing my certificate program, I excelled in MERN, SQL & NoSQL, and Javascript projects. Worked in several different groups throughout my bootcamp and was recognized as a proactive, resourceful, and persistent problem-solver.

#### **Technical Skills**

- Languages etc:CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Express.js, React.js, OOP, MERN
- Databases: SQL and NoSQL (MongoDB)
- Tools: Git, Heroku, MySQL Workbench, Mongo Atlas

# **Projects**

#### Weather Dashboard

- Dashboard with a search bar that allows the user to input a city, and pull its weather
- Technology used: HTML and CSS, Javascript, OpenWeatherMap API
- GitHub: https://github.com/ajdavis2424/Weather-App
- Project Deployment: <a href="https://ajdavis2424.github.io/Weather-App/">https://ajdavis2424.github.io/Weather-App/</a>

#### GoodMorning App

- This App allows users to receive news stories from their favorite sources, and save them in one location.
- Technology used: HTML and CSS, Javascript
- Front-end styling
- GitHub: https://github.com/strawhat19/GoodMorning
- Project Deployment: <a href="https://strawhat19.github.io/GoodMorning/">https://strawhat19.github.io/GoodMorning/</a>

### What's-Your-Deal App

- This app allows users to find and save their favorite stocks, as well as pull information on each company selected.
- Technology used: HTML and CSS, Javascript, M.E.R.N Stack, NPM packages
- Role: Front-end styling, connecting and creating Mongo database
- GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/strawhat19/Whats-Your-Deal">https://github.com/strawhat19/Whats-Your-Deal</a>
- Project Deployment: <a href="https://whats-your-deal.herokuapp.com/">https://whats-your-deal.herokuapp.com/</a>

### TuneTime App

- This App generates playlists based on the duration of a task or upcoming event
- Technology used: HTML and CSS, Javascript, Handlebars, SQL
- Role: Front-End styling, and collaborated to create SQL schema
- GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/d4nnyq88/tune-time">https://github.com/d4nnyq88/tune-time</a>
- Project Deployment: <a href="https://tune-time.heroku.app.com/">https://tune-time.heroku.app.com/</a>

# Experience

### Orangetheory Fitness, Tampa, FL - Coach and Trainer

Sep 2020 - Present

- Leading and motivating members during their workouts by communicating effectively and efficiently.
- Helping members set and achieve fitness goals by creating pockets of one on one time to create a plan..
- Highest class utilization in Tampa Bay Region.
- Ensure members used correct technique, and offered corrections if they're unable to execute movements.

### AmeriCare, Tampa, FL - Emergency Medical Responder

Feb 2020 - Oct 2020

- Responded to emergency and non-emergency calls and assisted EMT's with efficient and immediate care to the critically ill and injured.
- Transported patients to an appropriate treatment or medical facility.

#### Saint Leo University, Tampa, FL - Graduate Enrollment Counselor

Aug 2013 - Jan 2020

- Built relationships with students and answered questions regarding degree requirements, enrollment, and admissions.
- Achieved initial contact with prospective students, and continued to counsel them through the entire enrollment process.
- Received Director's Choice Award for Outstanding Service 2015-2017
- Assisted new teammates with assimilating to the demands of being an admissions counselor, and helped develop new programs and tools to establish new counselor self-sufficiency.

#### Education

Georgia Tech, Atlanta - Full-Stack Web Development Certificate	2021
Saint Leo University, Dade City - Master of Business Administration	2020
University of Tampa, Tampa - Bachelor of Arts: Government and World Affairs	2008